Guide to the Miriam Frank Oral Histories on Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer Activists in the Labor Movement OH.039
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Howard Wallace, April 8, 1995
  Tape #042: San Francisco gay/hippy scene, anti-war organizing, coming out in movement and influence of lesbian question in NOW 1971, bar world, gay liberation, drifting away from SWP, Maoists in Revolutionary Gay Men's Union, job at peanut factory early 1970's, start of Bay Area Gay Liberation, popularity of BAGL, Harvey Milk's populism, Board of Education campaign 1975, Coors boycott, Teamster Local 888. Allan Baird's work with gay community, brewery workers, national boycott organizer and AFL-CIO work 1980's.
  Tape #043: Coors campaign and lawsuit, gay community work and mass protests in BAGL, leftist splits, placement by Baird as first openly gay beer truck driver Teamsters Local 888, gay identity and Teamsters, AFL-CIO convention mid-1970's, clashes with Milk over Farmworkers grape boycott support, BAGL and building gay/labor consensus for city worker support mid-1970's, DC gay march and AFL-CIO headquarter reception 1987, recognition in SF labor movement, Local 250 Service Employees and work with Sal Rosselli of Theater Janitors Service Employees Local 9, their strike and gay community theater boycott first run of "Making Love."
  NOTE: Howard Wallace's work is also mentioned in interviews with Gary Dotterman, Tom Ammiano, Vince Quackenbush, Leslie Manning, Nancy Wohlforth, Walter Johnson, Allan Baird, Hank Wilson, and Sal Rosselli.
  - Original Recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 40)
  - Original Recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 41)
  - Original Recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 42)
  - Original Recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 43)
  - Access Audiocassette (Box 5, Audiocassette 40-43)
  - Access CD (Box 2, Cd OH.039.130-132)
- Karen Wheeler, March 26, 1995
  This interview took place in Boston, MA. Wheeler grew up in Connecticut, spent her teenage years in South Carolina as a "tomboy/nerd" and came out in Boston in 1973. Her interview covers the topics of lesbian bars/sports scene, her 1976 welder apprentice at Quincy Shipyard Local 5 Shipbuilders, left organizations, women union members' democracy issues, non-traditional work, lesbian workplace invisibility after-work culture, age, ethnic, racial and gender issues, asbestos, Boston City Hospital Service Employees Local 285, integration of lesbian and union life, gay/lesbian hospital workers, GALLAN and Fenway Clinic benefit, harassment, workplace romances and domestic partner benefits.
  - Original Recording (Box 8, Audiocassette 29)
  - Access Audiocassette (Box 4, Audiocassette 29)
  - Access CD (Box 2, Cd OH.039.138)
- Hank Wilson, April 12, 1995
  This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. Wilson was raised in Sacramento and was educated at UCLA and University of Wisconsin. His interview covers the topics of VISTA, anti-war activism, FBI harassment, his move to San Francisco in the early 1970's, Bay Area Gay Liberation, street organizing Castro, politics and Left, Board of Education anti-discrimination policy work with Tom Ammiano, parent support of gay teachers, lobbying, teachers coming out, Gay Teachers Coalition work with black community, Gay Democratic Club, Florida Save our Children, Briggs inititative, Larry Burner openly gay teacher in Healdsburg late 1970's, Gay Freedom Day visibility, youth suicide prevention, his 17 years of homeless work at the Ambassador Hotel and development of AIDS outreach.
  - Original Recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 53)
  - Original Recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 54)
  - Access Audiocassette (Box 5, Audiocassette 53-54)
  - Access CD (Box 2, Cd OH.039.134-135)
- Nancy Wohlforth, April 11, 1995
  This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. Wohlforth was raised in Milwaukee in a union family affiliated with AFSCME. Her interview covers the topics of socialist values, student/worker alliance 1968, feminism, socialist group (Workers League), Socialist Workers Party, VISTA, NYC anti-war work, SWP, Coors, gay community politics, gay/union coalition work, domestic partner benefits, VISTA welfare rights sit-ins, Textile Workers JP Stevens campaign, SWP Steelworkers insurgency and Lordstown Autoworkers, Office and Professional Local 3 union politics, Gay Freedom Day, gay indentity in OPEIU, CLUW and NOW in the early 1980's, clerical jobs, her election to Vice President of Local 3 as open lesbian, baiting, gay themes in Local 3 organizing campaigns, gay/lesbian presence in OPEIU, and support from union feminists.
  - Original Recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 48)
  - Original Recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 49)
  - Access Audiocassette (Box 5, Audiocassette 48-49)
  - Access CD (Box 2, Cd OH.039.139-140)
- Nancy Wohlforth, June 18, 2006
  This interview took place in Maryland.
  - Original Recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 118)
  - Original Recording (Box 9, Audiocassette 119)
  - Access CD (Box 2, Cd OH.039.141-142)
- Ron Woods, April 27, 1995
  This interview took place in Huntington Woods (Detroit). Woods was raised in a Detroit suburb in a construction union family. He was a member of Local 412 UAW. His interview covers the topics of coming out to his family, working overtime at Chrysler, details of mobilizing grass roots coalition and demonstrations against Cracker Barrel in autumn of 1991, zaps and corporate campaign tactics, press coverage leading to public exposure, his 4 year apprenticeship as an auto eletrician from 1986-1990, shop culture, homphobic factory scene, Cracker Barrel news stories and reactions, ostracism, harassment, death threats, his transfer to a new worksite in August, UAW solidarity civil rights story 1993, standing up to his manager, co-worker respect, campaigning for UAW 1995 Constitutional Convention delegate and being baited by his opponent.
  - Original Recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 56)
  - Original Recording (Box 7, Audiocassette 57)
  - Access Audiocassette (Box 5, Audiocassette 56-57)
  - Access CD (Box 2, Cd OH.039.136-137)